We're ready to go. See you given us the
We're good, all right good. Call the order today's meeting of the Miami special utility authority
Item two is invitation by the staff member of mustard sea Christian church Kyoto
Amy over's have Amy are you from my am I thought I recognized your last name
Well if you don't mind do the education and I understand you have a brief presentation
You want to give also about good plan. Okay, go ahead
We can get asked to see people around us through the youtube and pay a lot of attention to our hearts
That we would be a life and all the way saying all we do
Thank you
You're any you have a pretty soft voice. I speak up because there's a break of silence. You don't have a mind
I'm just around her and
And it's a second largest and each people with really entire world with a population of 120 million people
And of that population less than one percent
Most people have never heard the gospel never read the Bible never been to church and probably don't know Christians
So the need for the gospel here is very great
Currently there's only one church for every 16,700 people in one missionary every 60,000
And one I think about Japan
I think about women since the dream which says
and how we believe in him, of the name of our heart,
and how we hear and let someone think to see that,
and how we're thinking of their set.
And so, most of it's seen network,
it's our dream that there would be churches,
and it would all grow up to them,
and then that each person would have a chance to hear the gospel
and to respond to that.
So, my team and I are looking for those churches and individuals
that would be interested in partnering with us,
by nature, and this nature,
can get to Japan,
and I'm looking to raise $3,000,
and I'm looking for $10,000,
and one time support.
So, if there's a lot of activity,
interested in partnering with me in this,
let me know.
I have more permissions to give you an,
I would also love to sit down and share more about what's going on in Japan,
and I'm looking for some of you that's having a gift.
Thank you so much.
Thank you. Thank you.
Are you working with the Minister of Alliance?
No.
I would just recommend that you migrate
you out to that group also for support.
Okay?
All right.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Okay. Next item is the pledge.
We're going to stand back and up.
We'll see if you would do it by the flag.
We're going to apply the United States of America,
and it's really very public for which it stands.
One nation, another guy,
any witnessable with liberty and justice for all.
Thank you.
Okay.
Item 4 is public input unscheduled personal appearances,
and when the audience wishes to address the council
on any of the agenda items.
They're being not on a file's consent agenda staff
as we're recommending item 6 and 7,
which are the claims of the matter for the consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items,
they're going to obtain a motion please.
And a second.
Second.
Low call.
Johnson.
What's the answer?
Four ofster.
Lewis.
Short.
All right.
I made this a little bit C17.
There's 103A that humbored contracting
for any of the sanitary sewer project,
and approved contract contingent upon receive of all
required documents, Tyler.
You're on it.
But four Tyler gives the presentation out.
This is just more of a punitive order.
This was placed on the MSUA agenda inadvertently.
It should have been on the city council agenda.
But since we've already put it out of what I've asked Tyler to do,
is go ahead and make the presentation because it's pretty
pretty interesting what we're going to do.
But the actual bid award will be on the next city council agenda
on the consent agenda.
So on the next.
On the next tonight, our next meeting.
Our next meeting at all.
Yes.
So we're going to just ask that it be put off.
But since we're already geared up to give the presentation
we thought we'd give the presentation.
rotation to mine.
Yes, sir.
So do we get started with BRC?
You put up a bit, just look fine.
There, by any of you, it's actually going through the campus.
This is the airline through campus.
So you know what if you do?
I do my sliplining instead of going in an excavating the whole side.
I'm putting you pipe in.
They actually put a material in there.
I'm almost like a sock.
Run it all the way through the pipe and then cure it.
And then set up a type of control car through there with a little cutter.
And it cuts out all the surfaces.
So you don't go on there to start being the soil.
You know how to use excavations on your campus.
So it's kind of going to be projected to lessen any damage to the soil.
And what's the material they used?
This is a type of method.
This one's a belt sock.
They have either a fiber or a belt.
It's a material that we're using as a belt.
And it's infused with a rosin.
Yeah.
And then the rosin, the run ultra-hot water through it.
And that causes a reset up exactly.
This one is slightly different.
Instead of using the steam or the hot water to cure it,
this one's actually going to use UV light.
So we're not really losing very much diameter this way.
So we'll get it smooth.
I'm getting rid of the trees.
You know the trees get into the lines.
It removes all the tree roots from roots.
And you wear the pipes as a material to get a clay pipe.
I mean, it makes it one piece.
So we were safe to admit for this.
I'm a little bit old.
It's ninety-two thousand dollars.
So you can use it when we bring this back on the contingent of the city side.
And where is this going to start?
And where's it going to start?
It starts on ice-tree.
There in front of EO.
There's a manhole right there.
It'll start right there.
They'll actually insert their sock right there.
And they'll go to the health street.
The street that runs there by the stadium.
So let's see what I actually runs down.
Do this in our campus right there.
It's approximately 12 hundred and fifty feet.
Okay.
You get any time issues being exposed.
This getting occurred.
Now I don't believe so.
Okay.
Any other questions?
Interesting technology.
I guess we'll be seeing some of this on some of our other infrastructure down the road.
Yes.
Good.
Awesome.
Okay.
Thanks, Tyler.
Thank you.
So we're not actually, we're not voting on to award the bid.
This is really a council item.
And again, we will have it on the consent agenda at our committee.
Okay.
Any new business?
Staff reports are in your packet.
They're available for questions.
Any community announcements?
Do we have most to adjourn?
Make a motion.
Second.
We'll call.
For aster.
Aye.
We'll assign.
Western.
Johnson.
Sure.
Aye.
We will take just to the shop.
Right.
Like 30 seconds.
And then we're going to go out of the council.
Maybe.
So then we get the nod.
Yeah.
Maybe it's the nod.
Okay.
But we're going to call this regular meeting of the Miami City Council for today's date
and time.
Adam too, as Paul can put on schedule personal appearances and he wants to wish us to address
the city council on any of the agenda items.
There are being non-identious, consent agenda staff is recommending items for through seven, but
a consent agenda.
If there are no questions on any of those items, we're going to entertain a motion to entertain
the motion.
And a second?
Say, we'll call please.
Joneson, forster, requested, list, show.
All right.
Adam, A, is Civic Center and GM, rehab projects, the LNT maximum price for cross-winged
construction as construction manager at RIST of the city.
Danny, I don't have to pronounce your last name.
Danny's honor.
OK.
I mean, then Jeremy, are you here?
Yes.
OK.
Jeremy, I think the floor is yours.
Danny, do you want to make any, now this is something that we're, as you can tell, we're
getting ready to get this project started.
We need to have these approvals in order to get cross-winged to start the project.
OK.
Anybody have any questions?
Do you guys know?
I do the all-spec sheet, y'all are looking at them.
We've been this out.
I'm going to put one thing in there, but I can't remember if we're off the top of my head.
But we've been out for a week.
We've been through these, these are all of the first projectors that we came up with.
We've been through those that were with the old bloated, that we've been out and made sure
they were out of the form of the work on the project.
Not all of them were the bloated, there were a couple that we hired, but we weren't first that.
They just defined the events on the day.
So we threw them out, they did not call the specification at all.
You want me to do this down to this.
Well, Jeremy, with respect to that, about how much difference overall between those
roads, those roads that we want to do to make your needs, armies, and the final number.
Well, they didn't meet the specifications for the business process either.
So there was no reason.
But they were nine at the first one, the building in all of it was 9,500.
So that would be substantially low, just scary low to me.
Right.
And I understand that, but I still think it's important that we are typically like that
for the taxpayers, some of the reasons why.
I can read down through these, if anybody has any questions or...
I don't think it's necessary to read through them, but if everyone would take them in to kind
of review them, and if we have questions, we can ask, and again Dean or Tyler, if any of
either of you want to make any comment, I've got a question on HVAC system.
I think they were looking at a verbal...
refrigerant flow, is that what these were did?
These aren't gas, and then it is a VRF system, yes.
The gen in the state on the remain on gas, but it is a VRF system.
Okay, well it just carried the gym, but I know those systems carry.
It's going to have its own system, I'm not quite a confident.
Okay.
And then it came out of the one board to use it.
We're sadly the only ones that were able to.
That's because there's a unique system for a limo cloma.
Yeah, it is.
Okay.
So they are somebody that's done multiple and multiple states of the VRF system.
I've actually done three drawbacks with them in the last year, where they were with
a subcontractive that used to the VRF system, and job on persons, and they did a job
and things were going on.
So they're full of I.
Or they probably the only ones that could service the systems.
Well, I would say they have a very large service routine in the state of mind.
I read a little bit and honestly, I think, probably carrier has,
probably one of the better systems.
I don't know what they did with carrier.
They look at the Mitsubishi and there was three different approved vendors or manufacturers.
I think carrier wasn't on there, I think it was the Mitsubishi type and all.
No.
Yes.
I was just curious.
And regards to the Riffing systems, what are we looking at?
What type of Riffing system are we?
He's doing the barrel work on on the gym, and then it would be a polyISO with it.
It's going to be the same one.
Or just replace the natural system.
Pilling it completely off.
I'm going back.
You're going to put it off, then I'll just bring back.
It will be the same mod that...
Mod load.
The Fable Proove and the Handy.
They will take it all the way back to the dead and then I sell out the mod that I'll open.
Okay.
We don't predict any issues with the underneath it on the gym.
There is a unit price that we have.
for a replacement of a metal.
Okay.
Something that I wrote in the show on the spreadsheet.
Right.
It's an M-9 variable.
And that's why we kind of have contingency down there.
Right.
Cover some things.
We do know there is some haunting damage on some of the GM,
but that's going to have to be addressed.
And we just want to make sure we have it in there.
So we don't want it to detect damage.
We want to get above the bank.
What are the general conditions number?
What is that for?
We have a contingency fee at fund.
Yes.
And is it just for a moment?
Thanks.
A curve.
We're going to property the general conditions.
This is for my time problems.
Kind of.
Countdowns.
Okay.
So, you know, not specific product items, but.
Right.
Just general over it.
And then so.
Again, would you explain for the benefits of anybody that might be watching what construction
manager at risk in general?
Why are we taking this approach?
What's the benefit of the taxpayer?
The benefit to the taxpayer is that by having the same construction manager that is overseeing
all of the subs take care of it, you have the economies of scale, you have the ability
to work with that company, especially in a building like this that is 62 years old, that
we may not know exactly what we're going to get into as we were just talking about peeling
back the roof, we have a fairly good idea of what's going to be there, but just in case
we don't, we can work with them as a partner, work with their superintendents to make
sure that we are doing this efficiently.
So this is very similar to the way Red Robertson was done, it's a way that it can be done
very quickly, it's a way that's also very economical, because that way the left hand, the right
hand, they know what they're doing at every step of the way.
And then you're comfortable with this, where all those state statutes and everything, we're
in compliance, there's no issues.
There is, I guess, one possible savings that we could have under this agreement, because this
is the maximum bid, the projected maximum bid.
You will notice the second to last item is the performance and payment bonds, both under the state
statutes and all the rules and regulations, there's a possibility of waving some of those
bonds, specifically the payment bond, if that is something that you should want us to look
further into.
The legal question on it is with regards to our city charter, which under the current city charter,
since our new one has not yet been approved to our knowledge, it requires two separate
sureties, and so that's why it's there, but there's the possibility, if you, as the Council
want us to look at possibly waving the payment bond, that is a possibility that could save
us.
I guess we're saying, we're saying, yes, it's certainly save us, but move it up into the
contingency, and if that's not used to be given back, that would make most sense to me, because
then you don't have to change these numbers and these are the numbers, and if we find out that we can
remove the bonds with the relationship that we have in the city, we'll move it up into
the contingency, and it's not used, it's given back a minimum of the problem, that's my, that
would be the exact solution, so the statute's allowed us to do that.
the question is whether the charter does, but then the next question would be if we can,
would we want to do it? And that would have to be your decision based on how much trust we have in
believing that Crossland would pay all of the subcontractors and suppliers as we go along.
And again, I think with the project of the size and potential complexity,
we're going to run into things that we aren't aware of. And obviously those are going to be items
that we'll be bringing back to you if we have to have change orders. Again, has been was talking
about this issue. We just really were made aware of it a little while ago, but it is an option
that we want to look at because $17,000-$18,000 is a lot of money. And we could certainly use it for other things.
So, Ben, let me say it this way. It's sort of like a mechanic plane. It's basically protecting the city
from a mechanic's one. Correct. Correct. That we would be, under this, as it exists right now,
we would be actually Crossland would be buying the pass in the cost onto us.
A bond to ensure that all of those mechanics, the workers and the suppliers are paid and full.
And to a great degree, your decision is going to be based on your relationship with, and we have a
company here that has a very good track record in Miami and a good track record with a city.
So, and it's in here right now because our charter requires it. There are state statutes,
it permits you to. It's hard to have it or not had it as I understand. It's, we're still deliberating
on what exactly the charter requires. But because there's that question, it's in here at this point.
So, and I'm going to come back to that in a minute, and are there other questions about any of what's
been presented so far? What is the aluminum storefront in glazing in the west of America?
Would rock doors? Okay. Okay. Okay. One thing I will ask the deputy clerk to do is when these
minutes are written that we put this in in detail as to what is being approved in that way,
it will be in the official record as well. And how much of the building would you say is being touched by this project?
80 percent. Oh, I mean, you're the best one to tell us that. How much of the building?
You're, you're having a bit of 70 percent. On the HGAC, it's going to be a hundred percent.
Or 95 other than the big bang, the vice professor has their own experience. The pH and everything else
is going to be touched. The ledgerals are going to be 99 percent except for the water. Very soon.
small things. So in real, that would complete the work to 100% of the new work within a year
of each chapter. So maybe there's a huge amount that nobody's going to see, that 90,000
over here and in the gym.
In the gym, we are adding cool and capacity that we haven't had before.
We have 12 hours to do the work.
And so I ask all those questions because we're not going to have a brand new building, but
we're going to have pretty close. And the price for, we bid out before.
We're looking at six million dollars or so for a new building.
So in that context, I think this represents a good value for the taxpayers.
Well, and also I think over the last couple of years we've had structural analysis
done at this building, which came out fine.
There was some, at the time, there was some discussion about any health issues in this building.
There are none. In fact, we just had our air quality taken care of just a couple of months ago
and everything turned out very well.
You know, it's Kevin was saying they're going to be some of the parts of this building
of its past, like the boiler area and all that.
That we just basically closed up and done allow anybody in.
But from our employees and the citizens coming into this building,
they're going to be coming into a very sturdy, very refreshed building.
It's going to last another 60 years.
Well, I think that certainly prudent.
With respect to the performance and payment bond,
any idea when we might hear from the governor on our charter.
You know, that's an interesting question.
I should have tried calling the governor's office today.
I apologize, I didn't, but I won't be doing that.
They assured me that they would not be any sooner than the beginning of July
because of all the finishing up everything with regards to session.
Well, obviously, we're past the beginning of July, but I will get what the governor's office
and find out where we're at.
So are there any concerns with approving this amount tonight?
With the understanding that we may, at a later time,
move that performance bond money out or see if I have any concerns about doing it?
Well, we're giving you as the highest number.
So if we made any changes that would pull back to cost, not increase the cost.
The highest number, other than unforeseen,
well, yes, construction issues.
Highest number for what we're aware of.
Correct.
And of course, anything that goes about that, you'll be moving, making aware of it.
I have one question, it's kind of off of that,
in regards to the gymnasium.
One time, it was talked about bringing it more into ADA compliance.
This has nothing to do with that.
I just want to verify.
It's just strictly HVNC.
Okay, so the agenda item,
I guess it's not spelled out, it's calling for a vote,
but that's in effect what you're asking for.
This is going to be the plan that we move forward with.
Okay, we got a vote.
Second.
Vote office.
Mr. Johnson.
Weston.
Vice.
Lewis.
All right.
Thanks, Jeremy.
We're going forward to working with you on this project.
I'll give you a project manager.
Okay.
Good.
I didn't number nine.
M.O.U. with a kilometre following the environmental quality for a
mediation at 5.23.
Good rich.
And to approve the M.O.U.
and approve the city manager's signature.
Hi, Alicia.
This is exactly what we did about three months ago for the area of one of three
industry southeast, the district walking park.
They're going to go in.
They're going to remediate a little area on the shoulder park at 5.23.
It's going to be no cost in the city at all.
And they're going to fill it back in and take care of it.
And it's just O.B.Q. wants an M.O.U.U. with a score so that we know what they're going to
do when we're good with it.
That's nothing to do with anything other than 5.23.
Good rich, which is a final question.
Since there was an item in the median about the most recent lawsuit that was
filed and then, of course, the ongoing issues that we have with the owner of the property,
we thought it would be better to present it in this manner for the record in case anybody is
watching and understands what this is and what this is.
Okay.
Questions?
Do we have a motion to approve?
I'll make the motion.
And second.
Second.
Will?
What's the motion?
Lewis.
I.
Forster.
Johnson.
Schultz.
Adam.
Tim.
presentation of the Miami Public Library Summer Reading Program.
Judy.
Hi.
Sorry.
And we've had a very fun film.
Summer in the theater.
Let's get those.
We were fortunate enough to get to the park with the boys and girls club.
Summer School.
Also came to see us.
A long of all of our regular.
So we've had a great time.
Each Wednesday was a family day.
We call it.
Anybody ever can come?
We have picked performers.
One of those.
We haven't had the boys girls club because we've had almost three of their people there.
So.
Wow.
Good stuff.
We've been using that.
A little bit.
Here is the.
What do you think?
I don't think.
They're just getting scared, they're coming from a first century, they're from the
center school, and they are measuring an out of the nest, their yellow piece of paper
there, it is about five feet, and we learned about eagles and a different large birds
that day, and some of the nests can get to be as big as the nine feet, and so they were
doing one measuring, but it makes a nest, and it's a bunch of stuff.
Here, one of the challenges was the book, the boy who participates in the wind, and he
might think that that is a fantastic story about a boy that brought me energy to his
village in Africa by reading about the library, and so it gives a challenge to use
like those, and so we had all kinds of different books, and here's what we're going
to do in fact the boy who was born.
And what was the program that?
It was the Bill Christmasian.
The Bill Christmasian feels for kids, and if it's a very fun day, the presenter is awesome.
He said that's more for sure the opportunity.
Very interactive, kids got to put on his sort of costume and say that there's a
Native American here in Berriad, and that's a kept on, and they got to trick
row, there was just a ton of stuff, but they got to see it, there was really a couple.
Another component, part of the program is that kids read, and we'll have the books
that they read, and I just come in and have a book, and I just come in and have a book
and I'm going to go for a book for the kids, and I'm going to go for the book.
Some kids were saying that they could just come in, jump straight into a book, into a book.
Or we have one story there, so they use it as a book large as, like, not any Indian,
or they print the Book Proposes and stuff, so.
How do you find the store?
Does it have a library?
Is it a city or is it contributions or?
No.
No, it is just that one.
How do you put that?
Yeah.
These suggestions are really, right?
We had a total number of children in attendance this year was 1,000 to 143, with 3,000
sub-gated adults attending one family.
Is that your number out or down or is that about average?
No, the children in attendance was probably just exactly double.
What do you contribute that to?
Well, we got to partner with boys and girls' bodies.
Yes, yes.
We have a learning center comes at almost everything.
And we have that boys' girls club before.
But this time, instead of just coming to the performance days,
they also came to...
I can't say small groups.
days because they grew up 15. So and we would like the Lego challenge that was with
boys and boys. So they also brought them on audition days other than just performance days.
When you say books longed, how are these books chosen or picked or what?
Oh, it's just random. It's just random kids. Whatever they want to.
What is the, Vicki? What is the, as a educator? What is the book that the teachers have kids
do their points? What's that word I'm looking for?
Is it related reader?
It's so related reader. There we go.
AR books. Is there AR books there? I mean, not that it's going to be.
If the kids are able to choose from that as well. If I choose to put a book up.
It's just how we want to do that. Whatever they're kind of reading.
What are reading? It's cool.
Yeah.
Joby can I call an AR book or something?
Yeah. I mean, we can identify any of the people that we have as far as if they need an AR not.
Some of them are marked that if they're not marked, all you have to do is just
pull up a cab on them to tell you. Right. Right.
So before you go, Judy, since we're talking about reading, I saw something on the marquee about adult literacy
over view or margin of speaking to that for a minute. What's available and that is at Christian Park.
So the literacy program and that is for adults, 16 and older, that struggle with bringing
with a lot of people on community. And she's been doing some tour practice so that she can prepare
volunteers to go to school. But it's just one online. It's free training, it's free. One of my tutoring,
all I need to do is this and one of the library we can set up. It is housing the library.
It makes it through the program. That's right. Okay. Okay. Thank you. Thank you.
Miami Summer Wet Program. Gini and Alicia. How are we off today?
Okay. We actually, let me just introduce myself again. I'm Geese E. Grace and this is the
list of Braggaric. I took over this program as the director and moved around 2011.
Braggaric's been with me since 12, 11 and well. I was actually as my right hand since 12.
And we have never actually had the opportunity to come up here and present to you guys. This is something we are
completely ingrosed in. I do not know how to tell you. I lay in bed at night and think about full stuff that
it and stuff he does. And we've had a really good run and we just kind of let you know throughout the years
this is what we've grown immensely. I mean this year we had a before we go over the slide show. We
had a little bit of an obstacle to to climb. We have usually we have about five hundred enrolled and we'll
have kids come every year that are just.
How do you say it for a lot of better words?
Just do not have any opportunity whatsoever.
You would not believe here in my amount of boomerang
machines that we see so we're in the same clothes every day.
Do you not have adequate shoes,
are not able to have adequate toiletries
if they're have stuff like that?
And so a big thing that is really, really good working
on my heart in progress is purpose.
You know, we're able to feed them one square mill a day
at any end of the free lunch program.
But we wanted to do more for years.
And it's just been one week after another.
We could never get it pinned down in this year.
We actually made it happen.
Anya was able to come to us and service on site,
which was partly due to boys and girls clubbing
where they're at, we were able to kind of piggyback off
of them since they were going to R&B.
They were serving boys and girls clubbing.
We were able to utilize the facilities that we had and come
to serve us.
And on average, how many kids did we feed breakfast?
We had 160.
So average, about 160 kids every morning.
And you would believe that on us and that is
that we come to ask you to describe.
Thank you so much.
There's no way we could have done this without you.
And we just, that's really been working on.
Silly, we're growing.
And we just really wanted to show you guys kind of what we,
what we're about, what we've done,
the past few years.
And if you want to go ahead and play the slideshow,
and then afterwards, if you have any questions,
comments, concerns, anything, it may,
because I'm telling you, we need all we can get.
We've got to be on the side of any of you.
Right here, we were really excited about that,
our kids were pretty awesome.
That's our red group, our seven-year-olds.
Reloading was super fun, especially with those walkers.
We need to be pretty awesome.
Reloading were a team that day.
So that's why we got crazy dress up stuff growing.
Lots of American flag.
So why you're going through this realize
that we split our groups.
We have been split into seven and eight, nine and 10, 11 and 12,
13 and 14-year-olds.
So what you're seeing at some times is going to be,
we have our blue and our gold, which is our older two groups out there,
and we may have our younger two groups,
or we may split them up to the younger group with an older group,
because the youth of our community really are really
the step up and help each other.
And so we can kind of hear them into different events,
such as this gaming.
They were amazing for the older kids to help those
and gender kids.
This is breakfast in our blue and white building.
It was pretty fun times.
Kids were excited about it.
It took a lot of ownership and that program.
They cleaned up their tables every day to got the trash.
And again, why we've had to split our groups
as enrollment is huge.
We're not to go over the campus.
It was a good solid eight kids every day.
And now we've four over five hundred and row.
Nob certificate, you've seen numbers increase on a younger or older or is it all about that?
Seven-year-olds.
Yes, and you know we've actually had a pretty substantial increase in our 13 or 14-year-old kids.
We offer a program.
We work through a lot of the schools around here.
She is actually an active on our society.
Sponsor, I'm a student council sponsor at my school.
I teach at Wendock.
But our teachers at Berlin, and these kids have to complete community service to be a part of these organizations.
So we will let these kids come and volunteer their hours and you know work with the area of you.
And I know why kids, they have to have 10 hours of semester, how many years did they have to come?
Twenty total, okay.
So about the same.
And we'll have these kids come in and you know, every year we have a waiting list and come work for us.
But we want to do this.
We want to put you on the list, you know.
But this is like an amazing, awesome place if you have not ever been.
It's an unbelievable, it's fabulous.
I have never seen so much science, type you stuff.
I can spend all day in there.
It's hands on.
It'll allow the kids to get in and just go right after it.
You get to pay.
This is fun.
All that paid for our job is.
I got something to pay.
I don't care.
I know a lot of pictures are overload guys.
But this is our youth.
And we can't put stock in our youth.
Then our town is in borrow world.
I heard.
In the future.
What do you say?
It's forced.
You say town.
Are you pulling firm mind off?
I mean, what is this strictly my Emma?
Are you pulling?
We have very few kids.
I'm surrounded community because if a parent works here in the past,
we've always charged or took a donation.
I would love.
That's my goal.
Our big goal is to bring a bus from acting and pick up.
I like kids.
And why not kids?
And call ball kids.
Because I know it's all about county.
But we've got to do something.
We currently, for the kids to get there,
their parents bring them or somebody brings them drugs.
We want to fix them.
That's right.
And including commerce.
Yes.
We have one stop in time or stop.
But it's mainly all of those kids have more from my Emma addresses.
This was a former counselor and my name is Cody Larsen.
He came back because that kid that he was hugging.
That was his favorite favorite coach.
And he wanted him to present him his camera.
And he was like, oh, this is my little brother.
He's driving his little puppy wagon.
My mom and dad and his brother.
They've got puppies every year.
And the kids love it.
That's our goal group.
They completed a hundred safety.
education course this year, we have 100% pass rate.
We have fun taking pictures under one or two at the pool.
But lots of different avenues.
This is a recreation camp, but I'm really about the lifelong recreation.
A lot of people are basketball, football.
Let's just play that now.
That's why I add an archery.
That's why we add it under safety.
It's just a really good course, but the kids can take.
Lots of different activities utilized here at Ariana.
I'm really, we're probably going to talk about this.
We're going to grow up in great, great households.
We didn't have a lot of opportunity.
And trying to teach kids, you know,
I'll teach them to utilize what you're seeing, what your community has for free.
That's a big part of what we do.
But there's so much more that we've done in the past.
We've just been following the law in the presentation.
But because have any questions, comments?
Are they still going to the pool in the afternoon?
Is that still an option for them?
Yes.
In the big picture, yes.
I'm going to visualize it Friday.
Just our group.
And like we have discussed.
I mean, because they can't know.
It's being a principal.
These kids, some of these kids would not have a meal.
So the next, so, this came in.
That's who Danielle has.
And they, like I said, they are offering them that breakfast.
We make sure that they give that lunch.
If they want seconds on lunch, they give that seconds on lunch.
Because for some of these kids during that month of June,
that maybe the only time that they actually do eat well-balanced meals.
But that's so.
So is it a full week program?
Yes, sir.
And what limits you from being a six-week program?
I would say probably fun being at the most, I mean, because I guess.
Roughly, it costs us $1,000 a day to run a camp.
That's just in labor.
That's not an activity.
That's not even mileage for my gut strikers.
It's fun.
Also, you know, the people that I hired, the majority of the people that I hired are teachers.
I do have some area of youth.
I try to keep it, you know, 18 and older.
And a lot of them are so entangled in sports.
I know teachers, me as a teacher.
I don't necessarily want to work my whole summer.
I mean, so at the primary thing, only this happens.
Probably be fun.
And then, obviously, it would be staffing, being able to staff.
Because any of you does offer the free lunch program all summer.
Right.
Are you guys on our Facebook page?
Kiss.
I didn't see that up there on the slide, did I miss that?
I mean, it's not.
It's not.
But it's in a circle.
Okay.
Yeah.
program. All during that month I'm on there we're updating daily as well as any text that
we send out their order in mind. Go on there as well. We give them away to communicate with all
the parents so that we keep them informed. They can communicate back with us at any point in time
I've gotten to accept an impact. From here to your money to information about the next day and we leave that
money communication open so that they can reach us. And that's fully taken the load off of Jamie.
Jamie, how many calls did you have this year? I mean, was it?
I don't know if you're three this year. Two or three so. Two years ago before they started
Exactly. I used to, I used to, Jamie's giving this old flip phone because that would be
my work phone for the summer and I would have to have to upload minutes to it and for it literally.
When you give me like 30 minutes, pre-paid cards, I'm looking for this. Now, this isn't working.
So we had to have me implemented the reminder program. If you guys know what that is, it's usually
it's a one-way text, we can just say, hey, buses are running now. We're expecting your kid or
red group is going bowling tomorrow. Make sure they wear socks or they can bring money for
concessions, stuff like that. It's just a communication and they can respond back to that. Yes, they can
respond back. So you made a comment just then that red group is going, so we don't, the full number of
kids are not going to one of them. He's just not feasible to be able to do that. So you split in groups
take them different. Yes, right, they're amazing. We ended up taking weeks with, like I said,
one of those older groups, and a younger group, and we went one day, and then we took the other half the next day
to go because it just made it very, very feasible for us to do things on bowling, it's one group at a time.
Because at one point time we could take the whole group and we could design in the bowling alley and have
the problem. And we can't do that. Well, the good thing is, you know, they reminded all the
next year, we're very hopeful with the addition of the splash pan to the city. That's going to
offer you one more stop to go to utilize for the kids. I thank you for what you guys do. I know,
you know, as being a teacher, I'm married to one, and I know that you would really love to enjoy your
summers off. And for you guys to stand up and go and do that for the kids, especially the ones
that are less fortunate. It's great. And I appreciate you guys for doing that.
There's no good ones we want to impact them. Exactly. I'm sure. I'm going with your wife as a teacher.
I mean, those are the ones that we really do try and pull in, and we want to keep hold of them and let them realize
there's more than what they see on a daily basis. They can go out, they can go to college,
and then they come back and they get back to the communities of productive and work society.
That's really what we've tried to implode in our kids. I mean, literally we're not saying
well, I mean, I'm like beating their brains out and saying, hey, you've got to, I don't think these kids
are going to think, oh, that's my fault. It's a curie. Oh, my goodness. You know, but
you have to grow in love to me.
if you're not fit, I mean, it's only good deal.
And some of these kids say, get it.
But we got kids go, oh, you know, I just kind of get graduated,
a speech path program, oh, you know,
it's just like, I remember, you know, in this LP,
and she came back and visited, how many workers do we have
that four canbers at one point a third of our staff
has been to campus, and we know our routine,
and they have to ask, we run a program within,
but they can count through not only doing that,
like our own society, and our students can't look at them.
But when they turn 14, that's their last show with us.
They don't want to give us up.
So we offer them on a case by case basis,
we can say no, and they can kind of make a volunteer for us.
They know how they can work.
So we put them in the group, they can work.
After about last year, in that year, in 2016,
they have the ability to go through the interview process
and to be hired as an actual counselor at that point in time.
That third of our staff has done that, and has done that.
And that just grows every year,
that we have coming back because they believe in the program too.
OK, ladies, that was awesome.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I am 12.
We're in the agreement for softball and baseball fields
for third party rentals with up, David Pricing structure.
Hi.
I'm a little bit of background.
There's been a, and there has been implemented
a balkal football agreement that has to do
whatever gone through, and it's just going to reband it.
It looked around the area, and you can see what
we kind of charged around a four-state area.
And so what I have done is, but you have a big price structure
or a baseball and softball fields, and you can hear
some through this area of what would work best.
So overall, what I came up with is that
renting just a flat bee and then tackling on another food
for lights is the best way to go.
Learning as I go, how to structure this, I
would be how that in front of you, and our old agreement
to be had just a flat-range or just additional feed
or perpane.
So just some improvements that I have made on this form
is more information to fill out price structure,
insurance information that you don't have insurance
how to obtain that insurance, and just a brief policy
of understanding of what you're acquiring and what
rules and regulations that we have for the people
for the government.
Any questions?
So how long have you been doing this now?
The doing this hasn't been quite a year yet.
OK.
And it's probably been learning as I go.
What's your biggest challenge?
Probably the biggest challenge.
challenge of anticipation. Trying to get a community of all and folks on board and trying to let
people know that my illness is going to do more than just sports or else it's going to do
an instance as well.
Sure, you might want to mention that this is already gone through the CVV as well.
Oh, yes. This is gone through the CVV and parks board as well. They have a group, this price
structure, so it needs to be born to counsel to see if there is a group of all in this
or any questions.
Okay. Any questions for Charlie?
No, other than I appreciate everything you've done so far, Charlie. I know that this has
kind of been out of your will, house, but you've really wrapped your arms around it. I've
visited with Charlie with other individuals in regards to other different youth sports
and expressed our concern for whatever. It was worth and she's really in this town
you've sports and times everybody's got the great point from the sidelines. It's so it's
she takes a lot of advice and then runs with it.
So I appreciate what you've done.
Okay. We have a most to approve. Make a motion to approve.
And a second.
Second. Roll call.
Foraster.
Hi.
Lewis, hi. Western.
Johnson.
Hi.
Here on. Thank you.
Yep. I'd just like to say something very quickly. The last three items on the agenda were
initiatives by Alicia Jamie, Marsha, Amanda. Just to kind of highlight, sometimes we forget what
we're here and for. And to highlight a lot of the programs that we do terrific programs for our
youth.
And just thought a few minutes and one of our meetings just to highlight that was worthwhile.
And I wanted to thank them for that poor site. We were putting together the agenda and all
said, you know, we need to make these presentations. So I just wanted to thank them.
Okay.
I didn't 13.
Partition of three emergency scenes. Seeing the head signs and stands. She's using traffic accident
using our county tax.
Chief.
The firing problem I would like to purchase three emergency incident signs that in place
that traffic accident is that we received some training on TM. It's going to traffic incident
management system. And it's how to handle correct some of the interstate in the redways keep
firefighters in first responders saying, I'm going to a little video just going to show you what
the sign will apply.
A little bit about the 10 hour block flags that we did.
What we're asking our first responders.
And standing.
That's that's the sign right there.
Thank you.
We're about the word says emergency incident head.
You put it out about 500.
That's about to be from the incident.
Is it lighted?
No.
No, he's at the right word is it that we're trying to figure it out
Thank you, yeah, but it doesn't have likes on it as well. No, it just sets on the roadway and your car lights will make it visible, but
That's not the only thing that goes out on an incident, you know, he was about comes
I work with the first responder and he came on a traffic accident just this last week and had a horrible wreck and they didn't have this available
And it was just he was blinded by the flashers and
I mean, that's why I was wondering if it did have a light system on it that would know
It's just a way of early identification for traffic driver
Because, you know, as many things as we have today with cell phones and distractions, you know, when you've ever
Which is something we didn't decide
Now we carry that on your first responder vehicle
On three
And then the new rescue
Command be hickled too
It won't show you at 30 second
Okay
Over the last two decades
It's gotten more complex
It's gotten more demeaning
The sorts of threats and risks and situations that they face
The sorts of equipment
And the sorts of responses that they need to be prepared to deliver
Have gotten more complex
So trainings more important than ever
The risk-pocker safety learning network is the first and only 24-7-3-6-5
Also learning slowly
That's just a little bit of the video that
You know, that's in two videos training
And this is part of it and we thought we really did a bit of this
So two questions
The signs are training
You training
You go along with the video training
Yes, on how to block traffic
And how to set up the first need
Does it still require someone to physically hold that or
It's got a standard
Just leave it there
Okay
Do you have much money to do with that?
Pardon?
What money do you have to do with that?
Do you have to do it?
Oh, about 24,000 here
Yeah
I think that's about right
And we have about half of it
And we are navigated in the rest
We use for equipment
And you might remember about three years ago
We set up a process by which when we spend that money
We run a three-year like this
There was some of that was already committed in the budget
But if you said about half, right
Yes, it's on the digital fund
Okay
So in questions
Any more questions?
We have a motion
One second
Second
Roll call
Johnson
Thank you
Weston
Forster
Lewis
Hi
Item 14
Capital Ventures Government Relations
I see July claim of $3,000
There are any questions
or conversation on this item
Do we have a motion to approve?
I'll make a motion to approve.
I'll second it.
Okay, roll ball please.
Worcester?
Aye.
Johnson?
No.
Aye.
Item 15 is new business.
Any new business?
Being anything?
No, you're out here.
Item 16 is staff reports of reports on your packet.
If available in staff is present if there are any questions.
Item 17, Mayor and Council Committee announcement.
Any one of that one?
I just want to make something about being a share.
December 3.
That's getting kicked off.
Responderships out there.
All of that.
I don't have the windmider.
It's for the, you know, being off.
Not off hand.
I can't.
Where's the weather?
You can go to.
And I'll get that from the next meeting.
With that.
Responderships available.
And.
I'll kind of take it.
I just want to try to take it.
About tickets there.
Is that in December?
December.
December 3.
Okay.
And we're hoping any else.
I'm going to be in there.
Okay.
All right.
So the manager of communications team.
You know, I have two items.
Number one.
I just wanted to let you know that the application process for the
Serum shelters is closed.
And we had 145 applications.
We have funding for about half of that.
About 73.
We're going through the process right now.
But that will basically be at $1.046,000 grant coming into the community.
The portion per storm shelter is also paid for by the person applying for it as well.
So that is going through.
Just want to give you a quick update.
Secondly, this month.
I don't think we have anything planned for a study session for next week.
But I would like to point out that in August we have a fairly substantial number of things
that we'd like to bring to you.
With Ben's Hill.
We're in the process right now of looking at ordinances and policy changes.
And the significant number of them.
For example, in the police department.
Because of state questions 780 and 781.
There are a number of things that we have to change in our law that has to go along.
That lines of that.
Those new questions that we're approved by the voters.
Court fees.
I believe courts have updated some of the fees and fine structure that we have there.
That also includes code enforcement.
Some changes that we'd like to make some presentations on there.
Animal control.
I know that Ben has been working on a number of issues related to animal control.
A number of them that that.
Neal and and several other people that have been working on animal issues have suggested.
So we're bringing that before you.
There's some personal changes that are taking place.
Even a couple changes related to our firework's ordinance.
So instead of bringing it to you.
It kind of a group of fashion in which we bring a few and a few.
What we'd like to do is that our next study session.
bringing it to you on a whole package. A lot of them aren't related, but yet we're looking
at a number of different changes. This would be a good way to present them to you. It would
be the start of any kind of discussions before you would actually have to vote on them.
And it's also a good way to introduce them to the community as well. So I think that's what
we're planning in August. I said a number of these are very good. Some of them are probably
way overdue. But I do want to thank Ben and I want to thank the staff for working on
these because we recognize we need to bring these things up to speed. But we just didn't want
to overwhelm you on it, but we also wanted to make sure that we're doing it kind of a holistic
manner that it doesn't always seem like every council meeting you're wondering what's next.
So we're one of these. August 22nd. That would be our starting session to the month.
We have a meeting on the first and the 15th. And so the third Tuesday, the 22nd, the 22nd correct. So I just
want to give you a heads up on that. And you don't have anything for next week. No, I do
not unless you have some. So Melissa, if you'll get with me, we'll talk about that.
Anything? Is that it? That's it? Anything else anyone? All right. I'm 19 as you jump. We have a
most good one. You do that. And second, second, a little help please.
Show them since. Western. All right. Four, six, five, six, eight, six, eight.